Guide to the Kathy Cohn Knott Family Papers, 1922-1961 MS 1042
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Kathy Cohn Knott Family Papers
1922-1961
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Knott, Kathryn Cohn
MS 1042
.25 Linear Feet 1 box
One box of news clippings, correspondence, and event materials document some of the history of the Levy / Lipper / Cohn families from 1922 to 1961.
Biographical / Historical
Herman Levy (1840-1927) and Marie Auerbach Levy (1853-1926) emigrated from Germany with their families in the 1860s and married around 1875. The couple had several children, including Benherd (Ben) Mayer Levy (1882-1933). The couple is interred at Beth Israel Cemetery in Houston.
Arthur Lipper (1862-1924) was born in Mexico and Florence Larendon Lipper (1864-1955) was born in Texas. The two married around 1884 and had three children, including Mabel Lipper Levy (1887-1975). The couple is interred at Beth Israel Cemetery in Houston.
Ben and Mabel married around 1917 and had four children: Florence, Ben, Hortense, and Hildigarde. The couple is interred at Beth Israel Cemetery in Houston.
Hildegarde Levy (1921-2013) married Burton Cohn (1910-1993) and the couple had several children including Kathryn (Kathy) Cohn. Kathy married Tim Knott in 1977.
Content Description
News clippings, correspondence, and event materials document some of the history of the Levy / Lipper / Cohn families from 1922 to 1961.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were donated by Kathy Cohn Knott in 2022.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged chronologically in one series as follows:
Series I: General Series
Related Materials
MS 758, Levy / Cohen Family Papers
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life
Document Types
Correspondence; clippings (information artifacts)
Subjects (Persons)
Knott, Kathryn Cohn
- Series I: General
  - Teich Monument Works materials, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ben M. Levy bay home in Galveston (photocopy), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Article about Ben M. Levy's death, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sigma Alpha Rho dance booklet, 1939-06-08 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - George Lipper funeral materials, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Temple Beth Israel Religious School certificate of promotion, 1952-05-25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hortense Blum Lipper funeral register, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Florence Lipper article, ca. 1950s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Congregation Beth Israel confirmation program, 1961-05-20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Herman Levy's mausoleum photograph, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)